Finding Aid for Lima Township, Michigan records, 1836-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lima Township, Michigan records
1836-1974
Lima (Mich.: Township)
89189 Cb 2; CB Outsize; Cb Outsize
Township records from Lima Township, Washtenaw County, Michigan.
4 linear feet
99 oversize volumes
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records of School District no. 7 came through Mrs. James K Pollock (donor no. 1937 ) in 1944. The bulk of the records came from the Lima Township Board of Trustees (donor no. 5450 ) in 1983. Additional materials were received from Mrs. L.S. Seamans (donor no. 1566 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The record group is open to research.
Township records for Lima Township, Michigan.
This record group consists primarily of records maintained by the Lima Township Board of Trustees. The records includes tax assessment rolls, various birth and death records, road and highway records, proceedings of town board meetings, justice of the peace case book, and other records documenting township activities. Also included are records of School District no. 7.
Subjects:
Justices of the peace--Michigan--Lima (Township); Michigan. Justice of the Peace (Lima); Roads--Michigan--Lima (Township); Schools--Michigan--Lima (Township); Taxation--Michigan--Lima (Township); Lima (Mich.: Township)
- Assessment rolls and related
  - 1842
  - 1846?, Undated (Box 1)
  - 1844 (Box 1)
  - 1845 (Box 1)
  - 1847-1961, 91 oversize volumes
    (lacks 1848, 1852, 1858 and 1862-1864)
  - Records of taxable property in Lima Township, 1870s; 4 folders (Box 1)
- School District, No. 7, records
  - School record book
    - 1859-1875 (Box 1)
    - 1876-1899 (Box 1)
    - 1898-1910 (Box 1)
  - School directors account book
    - 1914-1932 (Box 1)
    - 1932-1936 (Box 1)
  - School Treasurer's account book, 1914-1940 (Box 1)
  - Class registers
    - 1875 (Box 2)
    - 1876 (Box 2)
    - 1879-1882 (Box 2)
    - 1883-1890 (Box 2)
    - 1895, 1898-1899 (Box 2)
    - 1900/01-1902/03 (Box 2)
    - 1903/04-1906/07 (Box 2)
    - 1907/08-1913/14 (Box 2)
    - 1914/15-1921/22 (Box 2)
    - 1922/23-1925 (Box 2)
  - Attendance and scholarship records
    - 1927/28 (Box 2)
    - 1928/29 (Box 2)
    - 1929/30 (Box 2)
    - 1930/31 (Box 2)
    - 1931/32 (Box 2)
    - 1932/33 (Box 2)
    - 1933/34 (Box 2)
    - 1934/35 (Box 2)
    - 1935/36 (Box 2)
    - 1936/37 (Box 2)
    - 1937/38 (Box 2)
    - 1939/40 (Box 2)
    - 1941/42 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous; include lease 1974 plan for school house, 1875 annual statistical reports, 1935-1973, school program, etc., 1875-1974 (Box 2)
- Other records
  - Register of births, 1906-1950 (Box 3)
    (missing 1948-1949)
  - Register of deaths, 1909-1951 (Box 3)
  - Chattel Mortgages record book, 1847-1879 (Box 3)
  - Record of Road Districts (also proceedings of Highway Commissioners), 1836-1854 (Box 3)
  - Proceedings of Highway Commissioners, 1855-1881 (Box 3)
  - Highway Fund accounts, 1923/24-1937/38 (Box 3)
  - Road District ledgers, 1919-1971; 3 volumes (Box 3)
  - School District ledgers, 1911-1948; 2 volumes (Box 3)
  - Justice of the Peace case book, 1879-1923 (Box 3)
    (scattered dates)
  - Petition for referendum re township zoning ordinance (Box 3)
  - Petition for referendum re sale of spirits, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Proceedings of Town Board Meetings, 1939-1961 (Box 4)
  - Contingent Fund ledgers
    - 1899-1932 (Box 4)
    - 1933-1949 (Box 4)
      (includes proceedings of Highway Commissioners, 1902-1915)
    - 1901-1948 (Box 4)
  - Supervisor's ledgers (W.P.A. inventories of property, 1935-1936; 2 volumes (Box 4)
  - Notebooks of township assessor, Leigh Beach (including herd record books (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Drain assessments
    - Mill Creek 1st payment, 1961
    - Mill Creek 2nd payment, 1961
    - Palmer-Baldwin, 1961
  - Registration Book, men
  - Registration Book, women
  - Plat book
  - Description of land parcels
  - Survey of Palmer's Subdivision No. 1, 1950 (Folder 1)